{
    "id": "9f4b516109a847f3a0861898346f4d41",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I hope he ……………………………. the plane tickets.",
            "description": "After I hope we use a present tense with a  future meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "didn't forget",
                "doesn't forget",
                "won't forget"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The forest was so dense we ………………………….. see through the trees.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "can't",
                "couldn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You will have to pay a fine if you ……………………………. to keep the appointment.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "fail",
                "will fail",
                "failed"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She forfeited the match when she …………………………… to play.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "refused",
                "would refuse",
                "has refused"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He brought ……………………………. a proposition that we all liked.",
            "description": "Forth means onward or forward in space.",
            "answers": [
                "forth",
                "fourth"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is quite close to several members of the ………………………… estate.",
            "description": "Fourth is next after third.",
            "answers": [
                "forth",
                "fourth"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The lawyer was ………………………….. a police officer.",
            "description": "Formerly means previously.",
            "answers": [
                "formally",
                "formerly",
                "former"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………….. since she dropped the skillet on her foot.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "was limping",
                "has been limping",
                "is limping"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We caught only a ……………………………. glimpse of the royal cavalcade.",
            "description": "Fleeting means swiftly passing.",
            "answers": [
                "flitting",
                "fleeting",
                "fleating"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… I love Sundays!",
            "description": "When how is used in exclamations, the verb comes after the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "How",
                "How do"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The train …………………………. at half past six.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about future events that are part of a time table.",
            "answers": [
                "will leave",
                "is leaving",
                "leaves"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Red color does not ………………………. me.",
            "description": "Suit refers to style and color. Fit refers to size and shape.",
            "answers": [
                "fit",
                "suit",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}